Finding Aid for Library (University of Michigan) publications, 1881-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Library (University of Michigan) publications 1881-2002, 1950-2001
University of Michigan. Library.
3.5 linear feet
05120 Bimu C 410 2
The Library publications record group includes bibliographies, reports, manuals, brochures, maps, guides, handouts, newsletters, posters, information packets, and other publications and ephemera produced by the University of Michigan Library system.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Periodic accessions are regularly received from the library (donor no. 1278 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
See the Library Records finding aid for the history of the University of Michigan library system.
The University of Michigan Library Publications records group consists of four series: University Library, 1916-2006; Divisional Libraries, 1881-2001; Library Development, ca 1965-2002; and Library Instructional Handouts Set, 1991-1999.
Researchers should note that, with the exception of Illuminator (in the Library Development series), all of the newsletters in the record group are more or less incomplete. More complete runs of certain titles, notably University Library Update, University of Michigan Librarian, and University of Michigan Library Newsletter, are held at the Harlan Hatcher Graduate Library. The University Library System also retains numerous additional library publications within its collections that are not included in this records group. Finally, some University of Michigan library publications (including the three newsletters named above) are catalogued separately within the Bentley Historical Library's holdings.
Subjects:
Academic Libraries--Michigan--Periodicals.; University of Michiagn. Library--Periodicals.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Library. Friends.
- University Library 1916-2006
  The University Library, 1916-2006 series consists of materials that were produced either by library administration in general or by sub-units, projects, and programs not affiliated with any particular individual library (with the exception of Library Development, which forms its own series).
  - Bibliographies undated (ca 1975-1977) (Box 1)
  - Bookmarks 1984-2001, undated (Box 1)
  - Brochures circa 1957-1994, undated 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Events
    - Building Dedications 1920, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Conferences, Symposia, and Talks
      - Announcements and Programs 1981-2001 (Box 1)
      - Proceedings 1985, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Exhibitions (Programs) 1967 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1987-2001 (Box 1)
    - Staff Receptions (Invitations) 1987-1991 (Box 1)
  - Guides 1943-1998, undated circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Handouts
    - Mirlyn 1988-2000, undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1977-2001, undated (Box 1)
  - Information Packets
    - Diversity circa 1992 (Box 1)
      (Peer Information Counseling and University Library Materials)
    - Introduction to the University Library 2002, 2005-2006 (Box 1)
    - MITS (Michigan Information Transfer Service) circa 1988 (Box 1)
  - Manuals circa 1986-1988, undated (Box 1)
  - Maps and Directories 1979-2001, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous Items about (not by) the Library
    - Faculty Appraisal of a University Library, University of Michigan Survey Research Center, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Final Report: 1981-1982 and 1982-1983 Library Use Studies, The University of Michigan, University of Michigan Survey Research Center, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Off-Campus Services of the University of Michigan Library, Association of College and Reference Libraries, 1956 (Box 1)
    - "Preservation at the University of Michigan," Conservation Administration News, no. 19, July 1984 (Box 1)
    - Report for Albert Kahn Associated Architects and Engineers, Inc.: Reference: University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Renovation of the General Library, Construction Consultants Inc., 1969 (Box 1)
    - 3 University Libraries: The General Library, The Undergraduate Library, The Clements Library, University of Michigan Office of Research Administration, 1965 (Box 1)
    - The University of Michigan Library Arena--Cultural and Technological Challenges, special theme issue of Library Hi-Tech, vol. 16, no. 1, 1998 (Box 1)
    - University Libraries Under Pressure, special issue of Research News, vol 35, no. 7-9, July-September 1984 (Box 1)
    - "The University of Michigan Library System: Amazingly Big, But Easy to Use", special insert to the University Record, ca. Fall 1984 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Database Bits, 1983-1985 (Box 1)
    - Digital Library Initiatives, 1988, undated (Box 1)
    - Information Transfer, January 1996 (Box 1)
    - JSTOR News, December 1995 (Box 1)
    - Message from the Dean, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - MIRLYN News, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - MITS News, 1989-1996 (Box 1)
    - M-LINK News, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
    - University Library Update, 1983-1991 (Box 1)
    - University of Michigan Librarian, 1978 (Box 1)
    - University of Michigan Library Newsletter, 1982-1994 (Box 1)
  - Posters circa 1980s-1990s (Box 1)
  - Reports
    - Annual Reports 1916-1945, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Strategic Planning Reports
      - Maintaining the Library's Excellence When the Past Will Not Be Prologue, January 1982 (Box 1)
      - Organization and the Individual: Planning and Change in the University of Michigan Library--Part 1: Report Submitted to the Director by the University Library Planning Committee, December 1974 (Box 1)
      - Organization and the Individual: Planning and Change in the University of Michigan Library--Part 2: Documents Supplement, December 1974 (Box 1)
      - Planning for the 1990s, September 1990 (Box 1)
      - Transition and Transformation: Realizing the University of the Future: A Strategic Plan for the University of Michigan Library, June 1995 (Box 1)
      - The University of Michigan Library: The Past as Prologue: A Three Year Report, 1988-1990, ca Fall 1990 (Box 1)
      - The University of Michigan Library in Transformation, A Four-Year Report, 1991-1994, circa 1995 (Box 1)
    - Topical Reports
      - Bibliographic Access in the University of Michigan Library: Part I: Report of the Working Group on the Closing of the Catalog, June 1978 (Box 1)
      - Bibliographic Access in the University of Michigan Library: Part II: Report of the Working Group on Bibliographic Access and Display Systems, June 1978 (Box 1)
      - Digital Library Program Briefing, The University of Michigan, March 1998 (Box 1)
      - The Future of Bibliographic Access in the University of Michigan Library, April 1978 (Box 1)
      - The Library and Its Users: A Report from the User-Study Project on Opinions, Attitudes, and Expectations of Patrons of the University of Michigan Library, September 1991 (Box 1)
      - Point of Intersection: The University Library and the Pluralistic Campus Community, November 1988 (Box 2)
        (Includes press release)
      - Point of Intersection II: The University Library Moves Towards Diversity, June 1990 (Box 2)
      - Point of Intersection III: A Periodic Report on the University Library's Efforts to Diversify its Staff, Collections, and Services, August 1998 (Box 2)
      - Technical Services Memorandum No. 7: Glossary of Technical Services Terms, February 1975 (Box 2)
  - Staff Manuals
    - Library Compensation Manual, undated (ca 1973) (Box 2)
    - Organization Charts (misc.) 1986 (Box 2)
    - Organization Charts: University Library of the University of Michigan, September 1967 (Box 2)
    - Staff Manual: Organization Charts: University Library of the University of Michigan, November 1972 (Box 2)
    - University Library Staff Development Program, 1986, 1989 (Box 2)
    - The University of Michigan Faculty Handbook: Primary Librarian Staff, May 1984 (Box 2)
    - University of Michigan University Library Staff Manual, 1954, 4 folders (Box 2)
      (Organization Charts, Administration, Collections, Personnel, Reader Services, and Technical Services sections; includes revisions, 1955-1990)
- Divisional Libraries 1881-2001
  The Divisional Libraries, 1881-2001 series includes publications from many of the various individual libraries that exist or have existed on campus. It should be noted that, while not technically 'divisional libraries,' materials produced specifically by the Harlan Hatcher Graduate Library and its predecessor the General Library are also included in this series.
  - Alfred Taubman Medical Library 1980-1989, undated (ca 1970s-1980s) (Box 2)
    (Includes items form the earlier Medical Center Library)
  - Art and Architecture Library 1988-1989, undated (Box 2)
    (Includes items from the earlier Architecture Library)
  - Asia Library 1965-1990 (Box 2)
  - Dentistry Library circa 1980s (Box 2)
  - Engineering Libraries
    (Transportation Library, Engineering and Transportation Library, North Engineering Library)
    - Miscellaneous 1929, circa 1964, 1987-1989 (Box 2)
    - Newsletters
      - Engineering Libraries News, April 1987-January 1991, 2 folders (Box 2)
        (supercedes Engineering Library News)
      - Engineering Library News, February 1987 (Box 2)
        (supercedes Library News, precedes Engineering Libraries News)
      - Library News, September 1985-May 1986 (Box 2)
        (precedes Engineering Library News)
  - Film and Video Library
    - Catalogs 1989, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Filmographies 1989, undated (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1989, undated (Box 2)
  - General Library 1881, 1922-1946 (Box 2)
  - Harlan Hatcher Graduate Library
    - Bibliographies--Graduate Library Guide series 1973-1975 (Box 2)
    - Bibliographies--Miscellaneous 1993, undated (Box 2)
    - Bookmarks circa 1990s (Box 2)
    - Brochures 1986, 1992, circa 1980s-2000s (Box 2)
    - Events 1991-1991, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 2)
    - Guides 1975-1995, circa 1970s-2000s (Box 2)
    - Handouts 1978-2001, circa 1970s-2000s (Box 2)
    - Newsletters
      - Graduate Library News and Information, Fall 1995-Winter 1996 (Box 2)
      - Graduate Library Newsletter, December 1975-April 1988 (Box 2)
    - Reports
      - The 'At-Risk' Faculty: An Information Technology-Based Program of Research Support, August 1987 (Box 2)
      - The Humanistic Scholars Project: Final Report to the Council on Library Resources, November 1986 (Box 2)
      - Libraries and Economic Development: An Idea and Resource Guide to Stimulate Thought and Encourage Action, June 1991 (Box 2)
      - Faculty Support Program: An Information Technology-Based Program of Research Support, August 1987 (Box 2)
      - Faculty Support Program: An Information Technology-Based Program of Research Support, December 1987 (Box 2)
  - Media Union / Duderstadt Center 1996 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Libraries 1991, 2001, undated (ca 1960s-1990s) (Box 2)
    (Bureau of Government Library, Chemistry Library, Dearborn Campus Library, Education Library, Kresge Business Administration Library, Math Library, Museums Library, Phoenix Library, Physics/Astronomy Library, Social Work Library)
  - Natural Science / Natural Resources Library
    - Bibliographies
      - Museums, Natural Science, and Natural Resources Library New Book List, Summer 1977-June 1980 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous 1981-1995, undated (ca 1970s-1990s) (Box 2)
  - Public Health Library / PHISA (Public Health Information Services and Access) 1989 (Box 2)
  - Shapiro Science Library 1995, 1999, undated (Box 2)
  - Special Collections Library (Box 3)
    (Earlier called the [Library] Department of Rare Books and Special Collections)
    - Event Invitations and Announcements 1989-2001, undated (Box 3)
    - Exhibit Programs 1967-2000, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous 1987-1989, undated (Box 3)
    - Newsletter-- Judaic Journeys, 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - Undergraduate Library (UGL / UGLi) / Shapiro Undergraduate Library
    - Anthologies 1971, undated (ca 1970s-1980s) (Box 3)
      - Café Shapiro 2000 (Box 3)
    - Brochures 1971, undated (ca 1970s-1980s) (Box 3)
    - Guides 1988, undated (circa 1960s-1980s (Box 3)
    - Handouts--Instructional 1987-1989, undated (Box 3)
    - Handouts--Miscellaneous 1978-2001, undated (Box 3)
    - Information Packets for Faculty 1987-1989 (Box 3)
    - Manuals 1979, 1984, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous 1968, 1988-2000, undated (Box 3)
    - Newsletters
      - Construction Update News, June 1993-July 1994 (Box 3)
      - News From the Undergrad!, Fall/Winter 1988-Fall 1990 (Box 3)
        (supercedes UGL News)
      - UGL News, Fall 1984-February 1988 (Box 3)
        (precedes News From the Undergrad!, supercedes UGLi News)
      - UGLi News, Fall 1977-Fall 1980 (Box 3)
        (precedes UGL News)
    - Peer Information Counseling Program 1987-1994, undated (Box 3)
    - Report-- Renovation of the University of Michigan Undergraduate Library, June 1992 (Box 3)
- Library Development circa 1965-2002
  The Library Development, ca 1965-2002 series includes materials from the library development office as well as from the Friends of the Library. Highlights of this series are the keepsakes--facsimiles produced by the Friends of the Library from original materials held by Special Collections. Additionally, the series contains bookmarks, brochures, invitations, case statements, reports, the newsletter Illuminator, and fundraising appeals.
  - Bookmarks 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - Brochures, Invitations, and Appeals
    - Miscellaneous 1987-2001, undated (Box 3)
    - Programs and Events 1987, 1992-1995, 2004 (Box 3)
  - Case Statements
    - Library Giving Opportunities, 1993 (Box 3)
    - More Room for Books...More Room for Readers: Proposed Graduate Library, The University of Michigan $55 Million Program to Ensure the Vital Margin, circa 1965-1967 (Box 3)
  - Keepsake Series
    - Keepsake no. 1: Ancient and Modern Michilimackinac, Including an Account of the Controversy Between Mackinac and the Mormons, by James Jesse Strang, 1856 (facsimile 1987) (Box 3)
      (also includes note from the director)
    - Keepsake no. 2: Mitchell's Map of Michigan, 1834 (facsimile December 1988) (Box 3)
      (also includes packaging and limited-edition note)
    - Keepsake no. 3: The Fast Mail poster, 1875 (Box 3)
      (facsimile December 1989)
      (also includes note from the director, limited edition note, and color transparency)
  - Newsletter-- Illuminator, 1989-2004, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Reports-- A Message from the Director, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
- Library Handouts Set 1991-1999
  The series, Library Instructional Handouts Set, 1991-1999, is a series of handouts that arrived from the library as a set. Most of these handouts were printed from the World Wide Web. The handouts are arranged in the order of their accompanying index, a copy of which follows this finding aid as an appendix. The series also includes handouts that were filed with the set; they have been noted as additions in the index.
  - Index April 1999 (Box 3)
  - Handout Template circa 1999 (Box 3)
  - Dentistry Library 1996 (Box 3)
  - Digital Library 1999 (Box 3)
  - Documents Center 1999, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Film and Video Library 1998 (Box 3)
  - Hatcher Graduate Library 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Hatcher Circulation 1991-1999 (Box 3)
  - Interlibrary Loan 1998-1999 (Box 4)
  - Knowledge Navigation Center circa 1999 (Box 4)
  - Media Union Subject Guides 1996-1998, 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Media Union 1996-1999 (Box 4)
  - MIRLYN 1999 (Box 4)
  - Music Library circa 1999 (Box 4)
  - Museums Library 1996-1998 (Box 4)
  - PHISA (Public Health Information Services and Access) 1999 (Box 4)
  - Public Health Subject Guides 1994-1998
    - Photoduplication 1999 (Box 4)
    - Reserves circa 1999 (Box 4)
    - Serials/Microforms 1998 (Box 4)
    - Shapiro Science Library circa 1999 (Box 4)
    - Shapiro Undergraduate Library 1995-1998 (Box 4)
    - Social Work Library circa 1999 (Box 4)
    - Alfred Taubman Medical Library circa 1999 (Box 4)
    - Fine Arts Library 1998 (Box 4)
    - Slavic, Russian, and Eastern European Handouts 1993-1999 (Box 4)
      (originating library unknown)